Josh Woodcock // Full-Stack Software Engineer

832-247-8742 // josh@j0w0.com // github.com/j0w0 // j0w0.com // linkedin.com/in/j0w0

Full-Stack Software Engineer specializing in front-end development, experienced in building websites and web application user interfaces that improve efficiency and automate processes.

Technologies: React, Redux, JavaScript, TypeScript, Next.js, HTML, CSS, UI design libraries (Ant Design, Bootstrap, Tailwind), Git, Jira, CI/CD and cloud-based deployment services (AWS, Netlify, Vercel, Heroku), creating and consuming REST APIs (Google Maps, YouTube, Vimeo, Stripe, SendGrid, Twilio), GraphQL, Firebase, MySQL, PostgreSQL, PHP, Wordpress. My web development portfolio is available on my website and code samples are available on my GitHub.

Experience

Front-End Software Developer

Visit Widget | March 2023-Present | Austin, Texas

- Migrate Rails app to React and implement new designs based on Ant Design UI library.
- Extend and customize client CMS environments to allow for data-syncing capabilities in the Visit Widget platform.
- Develop features and enhancements for the Visit Widget platform and client websites.
- Tech stack used includes React, Redux, TypeScript, JavaScript, Ant Design, HTML, CSS, PHP, Wordpress.

Full-Stack Developer

Hahn | Contract | May 2022-December 2022 | Austin, Texas

- Overhauled legacy Learning Management System by developing a new system with React and Wordpress, resulting in quicker and more intuitive content entry, member usability, and a decrease in loading times.
- Develop, implement, and maintain new features for client websites, apps, and content management systems.
- Tech stack used includes React, JavaScript, HTML, CSS and SCSS, PHP, MySQL, Wordpress.

Front-End Software Engineer

Music Audience Exchange (MAX) | January 2021–May 2022 | Austin, Texas

- Developed front end of brand and artist web apps for streaming concerts, including real-time chat and donations.
- Simplified development process for quicker turnaround by creating standardized templates for content and layout.
- Tech stack used includes React, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Styled Components, Google Firebase.

Front-End / UX Developer

Remedy Urgent Care | January 2019-July 2020 | Austin, Texas

- Streamlined and refactored urgent care web app that won two stages of funding for the start-up, increased appointment bookings by over 1000% in the first three months, and decreased service coordinator call times by over 25%.
- Tech stack used includes JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, PHP, MySQL, Wordpress, Twilio, Stripe, WooCommerce.

MIS Web Developer

Ford Audio-Video | January 2017-January 2019 | Austin, Texas

- Developed and maintained Marketing's full-stack web apps for events and company's custom Wordpress website.
- Tech stack used includes HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery, PHP, MySQL, Wordpress, Twilio, Stripe.

Education

Texas State University